obama.org 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Obama Foundation

This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by The Barack Obama Foundation (“BOF”).  This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our websites, mobile sites, mobile applications and other online services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Sites”) or when you otherwise interact with us.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you an email notification).  We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Sites to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

### Collection of Information

Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us.  For example, we collect information when you sign up to receive email or text message updates, fill out a form, send us an email, communicate with us via third party social media sites, request information, respond to our requests, or otherwise communicate with us.  The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, postal address, phone number, credit card number, photos, videos, audio recordings and other information you choose to provide.

_Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Sites_

When you access or use our Sites, we automatically collect information about you, including:

Log Information:  We log information about your use of the Sites, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Sites.  
Device Information:  We may collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Sites, including the hardware model, operating system and version, device identifiers and mobile network information.  
Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:  We use various technologies to collect information, and this may include sending cookies to your computer or mobile device.  Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that helps us to improve our Sites and your experience, see which areas and features of our Sites are popular and count visits.  We may also collect information using web beacons (also known as “tracking pixels”).  Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Sites or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and determine whether an email has been opened and acted upon.  For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see “Your Choices” below.

_Information We Collect From Other Sources_

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Sites.  For example if you create or log into your account through a social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, account information and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site.

### Use of Information

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Sites
  * Send you confirmations, technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages
  * To request feedback and to otherwise contact you about your use of the Sites
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service
  * To send you newsletters and otherwise provide you with information or services you request or that we think will be of interest to you
  * To solicit volunteers, donations and support for BOF
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Sites
  * Personalize and improve the Sites
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service
  * Carry out any other purpose for which the information was collected

BOF is based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law.  By accessing or using the Sites or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S. and other countries.

### Sharing of Information

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

With vendors, consultants and other service providers or volunteers who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf;  
In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with any applicable law, regulation or legal process, or as otherwise required by any applicable law, rule or regulation;  
If we believe your actions are inconsistent with the spirit or language of our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of BOF, its employees, volunteers, constituents or others;  
In connection with, or during negotiations of, any reorganization, formation of a new or successor organization, asset sale or transfer, financing or lending transaction or in any other situation where personal information may be disclosed or transferred as one of the assets of BOF; and  
With your consent or at your direction, including if we notify you through our Sites that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information.

We may also share aggregated or anonymized information that does not directly identify you.

### Social Sharing Features

The Sites may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook “Like” button), which let you share actions you take on our Sites with other media, and vice versa.  The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature.  For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

_Analytics Services Provided by Others_

We may allow third parties to use cookies or other technologies to provide analytics services.  These entities may collect information about your use of the Sites and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information.  This information may be used by BOF and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, customize your experience and better understand your online activity.

_Security_

BOF takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

### Your Choices

_Cookies_

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default.  If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies.  Removing or rejecting browser cookies does not necessarily affect third party flash cookies used in connection with our Sites.  To delete or disable flash cookies please visit www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security for more information.  Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Sites.

_Promotional Communications_

You may opt out of receiving text messages, updates and newsletters  by following the instructions in those emails or text messages.  If you opt out, we may still send you other types of emails, such as those about your use of the Sites or any transactions.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#4920272f2609262b28242867263b2e).

Last updated March 20, 2014
